# Lee Jones

Berkshire, UK • +447785714507 • lee.jones@belisariussolutionslimited.com • LinkedIn

#### **Professional Profile**

I am an experienced IT leader with an extensive track record for delivering people, process & digital business change initiatives at global scale in complex, multi-stakeholder business environments. Very effective at enhancing governance, managing risk, ensuring compliance and driving major performance improvements across IT teams and services. I bring a depth of IT and programme leadership insight, including an expert knowledge of infrastructure, transformation, restructuring, process improvement and service integration and delivery. I have excelled in consultancy roles delivering Digital and Transformation programs, including Organisational Change Management, Product Ownership, Program Management and major systems transition.

I am well versed in both Waterfall and Agile approaches to both Digital and more traditional project assignments. Adept in supporting transition activity and ensuring that IT services are aligned and underpin key drivers within the business. Open, adaptable and collaborative, I ensure that key issues are identified and addressed whilst establishing strong team unity. I have a proven reputation for successfully delivering services and key projects to customers and I have managed and worked in international mixed teams of clients, consultants, vendors and contractors. I have excellent relationship skills and I develop strong and trusting engagements with clients when successfully fulfilling project assignments and interim roles.

# **KEY EXPERTISE**

IT Governance Service Management IT Organisational Design Cost & Value Optimisation Change & Transition
Project Management
Leadership & Innovation
Infrastructure & Operations

Digital Transformation Application Rationalisation Performance Measurement Portfolio Management

## **CAREER HIGHLIGHTS**

**Belisarius Solutions Limited Senior Project & IT Operations Manager** 

2012 - 2020

#### **IT Services consultant**

Present

• Helping a major US Software and Services company to review service competencies and make recommendations for improving IT capability for a large Middle East government client.

# Maersk Oil & Gas / Total - Senior Project & Transition Manager

(2017 - 2020)

- Spearheaded a **global application consolidation and rationalisation programme**, transforming global operations sourcing strategy and support. Integrated Cloud and infrastructure services following a significant business transformation. Managed post-acquisition IT integration and **successful transition of applications and services to Total**.
- **Reduced application footprint by 50%** and established a consolidated IT support team, delivering a **more efficient and effective global service at a reduced cost.**
- Project managed the transfer of MOG corporate information systems to Total. Existing legacy
  environment was a very large, complex, undocumented 30 year old bespoke system and had to build
  and develop a team to successfully manage and document the processes and ERP and system
  interfaces to successfully complete the program to allow MOG core infrastructure to be
  decommissioned on schedule.

# Cognizant Programme Management - Programme Manager

(2012 - 2017)

Working full time for Maersk client, managed large projects and transformation activities and filling interim leadership and delivery roles in the global IT function based in Copenhagen.

- Established a global support organisation, providing robust technical applications support to all Maersk 0&G locations covering 6000 staff. This **drove major productivity and efficiency** improvements, addressed significant communication issues, improved satisfaction rating from below 75% to 99%, reduced incidents and increased availability and responsiveness.
- Led outsourcing of IT support and application services and **established effective service** management processes (ITIL) and governance model.
- Implemented a global service catalogue and technical software license model with **significant commercial and business efficiencies.**
- Collaborated with key stakeholders and IT teams to implement standardised and consistent service management best practices, including demand management and project handover to support, across the organisation.
- **Drove efficiencies to manage application development and deployment** of both large scale systems and client application refresh using Agile project delivery methods.
- **Delivered performance improvements** through development and establishment of a global support model for data information management services, including coaching and mentoring and establishing an industry recognised COE (Centre of Excellence). Executed GDPR compliance programme.

# BP 1996-2011 Global Operations & Infrastructure Manager 2005 - 2011

Responsible for global infrastructure management, hosting and operational support: leadership of teams of 100+, service delivery complex infrastructure, ensuring compliance and heading large system implementations and IT transformation projects. Ensuring operational integrity, leveraging scale and optimising project delivery to enable world class services were the key deliverables of the role.

- **Drove major service level improvements globally** through established robust performance management governance, including introduction of harmonised KPIs.
- **Significantly reduced costs and improved flexibility** through data centre implementation, migration and consolidation. Managed full service support and operations for BPs European Mega Data Centre.
- Successfully managed large system & ERP deployments, client desktop refresh programs and, as global operations SPOC, implemented a new treasury system with annual \$multi-billion turnover.
- **Enhanced financial transparency and regulatory compliance** through global governance transformation.
- **Consistently achieved multi-million cost savings targets** through system consolidation, supplier negotiation and service rationalisation.
- Positioned IT as a strategic partner, resolving a wide array of commercial challenges, controlling
  costs and managing risk.
- BPs hosting manager responsible for global capacity management and ensuring supply and demand were aligned to meet business forecast requirements.

Downstream - Telecommunications and Hosting Manager 2001 - 2005 Burmah Castrol - Infrastructure and Operations Support Manager 1996 - 2000

EARLY CAREER	
Valeo (France) Automotive	
PC & Network Support Manager	1994 -1996
Swansea City Council	
Senior PC Support Officer	1989- 1993
Management Services Graduate Trainee	1987- 1989
EDUCATION & PROFESSIONAL ACCREDITATIONS	

University of Wales, Swansea, Master of Arts (History) Project Management Institute, PMP University of Wales, Swansea, Bachelor of Arts (History) ITIL, Service Management (V3)